DANNY ANDERSO danny-anderson.com/http://danny-anderson.com/

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

A software engineer with seven years of front and back-end development experience, I'm interested in finding a position where I can further my understanding of ruby and/or rails in a team environment with a focus on TDD or BDD.

Skills

Server Side

Front End

Ruby and PHP

Responsive design

Technical

HTML5	Haml	Markdown	CSS3	SASS
Javascript	Coffeescript	jQuery	PHP	Git
Ruby/Rails	Vim	Linux	MySQL	MongoDB
MS SQL	Shell Scripting			

Experiences

TWG Plus - Higher Education Marketing

15 March 2013 - Present

Application Developer

Originally hired to take over a legacy campaign management application built in Rails, I stepped into a number of other roles as needed including working as the front end developer on client sites for several months while interviewing to hire a dedicated front end developer. I managed our front end developer and several outsource developers.

Mindwave Research

Survey Programmer

1 September 2010 - 15 March 2013

Worked with project staff to develop international web based surveys for numerous clients. Implemented web based tools to improve internal business processes. Led the initiative to get all internal development under version control using Git and automated deployment using Capistrano.

Freelance Software Developer

1 May 2006 - 1 November 2010

I worked closely with a partner who handled all the graphic design work on these projects while I handled all of the development

Projects

Survey Programming

18 February 2013 - 5 April 2014

Programmed national/international market research studies primarily focused on B2B technology companies. Developed extensions for our survey platform using jQuery and occasionally C# with the survey platforms SDK to create dll's.

TAP

18 February 2013 - 5 April 2014

Programmed national/international market research studies primarily focused on B2B technology companies. Developed extensions for our survey platform using jQuery and occasionally C# with the survey platforms SDK to create dll's.s a market research study with a data portal which allows media planners to view the aggregate survey results in various ways to help guide their marketing and media planning. I worked with the lead programmer and our market research scientist to determine the feasibility of programming particular methodologies.

Translation Module

18 February 2013 - 5 April 2014

PHP - MySQL - This allowed a user to upload an XML translation file generated by our survey design tool. The file was reformatted for easier use by our translation vendors and the files they returned were converted back to the format our survey design client required. This tool reduced the time spent importing text for each language from over half a day to under half an hour as well as reducing the amount of error in the resulting import.

Sample Manager

18 February 2013 - 5 April 2014

Florence - Tuscany Italy

Generated unique links for our surveys. Each link was tied to a specific survey, language, and vendor with up to a million links created per survey. The system also tracked which links were used and various metrics such as the last login time for each link.

Education

Berklee College of Music, Boston, Massachusetts USA

1 June 1999 - 31 May 2001

Bachelor of Music, magna cum laude

<u>Austin Community College</u>, Austin, Texas USA

1 January 2006 - 1 January 2009

Course work in Computer Science, with a focus on C++ and Object Oriented Programming in Java